Soviet Union Jewish Subject Files, Inclusive: 1952-2002, undated, Bulk: 1971-1992, undated
Baylor University, The Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society
- General, 1952-2002, undated; 1
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Solidarity. Appeals. General, 1965, 1972-1987 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Entry Visas Refused to Foreigners, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Foreign Governments Concern over Soviet Jewry, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Soviet Jews Appeal to Foreign Governments, International Organizations, 1977, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Soviet Jewry Question at Western (International) Conferences, 1975, 1983, 1986, undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions (1 of 10), 1965-1970 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions (2 of 10), 1971 January-May (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions (3 of 10), 1971 June-December (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions (4 of 10), 1972 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions (5 of 10), 1973 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions (6 of 10), 1974-1977 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions (7 of 10), 1978-1980 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions (8 of 10), 1981-1983 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions (9 of 10), 1984-1986 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions (10 of 10), 1987-1989, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions. British Churches and Clergy, 1974-1986 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions. British Government, 1974-1987 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions. Campaign Groups, 1975-1985 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions. Campaign Groups. Board of Deputies, 1975-1978 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions. 35’s Women’s Campaign for Soviet Jewry, 1975-1985 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions. Student and Academic Groups, 1968, 1974-1985 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions. Association of Jewish Servicemen, 1978-1981, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions. National Youth Council for Soviet Jewry, 1976-1981 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions. European Interparliamentary Group, 1981-1984 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions. National Council for Soviet Jewry, 1975-1986 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions. Disruptions during Visits of Groups and Individuals, 1974-1986 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions. Street Demonstrations. Vladimir and Maria Slepak, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions. Street Demonstrations. Iosif Begun, 1977, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions. Street Demonstrations. Anatoly Shcharansky, 1977, 1981-1984 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions. Reactions in Soviet Press, 1974-1978 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions. Awards Bestowed on Soviet Jews, 1981-1986 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Western Reactions. General Opinion, 1974-1986 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Foreign Organizations. General, 1974-1987 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Soviet Delegations’ Visits Abroad, 1968, 1984-1987, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. Visits from Foreign Delegations, 1966-1988, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Jews in the USSR. Underground Religious Activities. Meetings, 1976-1986 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Jews in the USSR. Activities Disapproved by the State. Protests. General, 1973-1988 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Jews in the USSR. Activities Disapproved by the State. Written Protests to Authorities, 1974-1985 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Jews in the USSR. Activities Disapproved by the State. Hunger Strikes, 1971-1987 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Jews in the USSR. Activities Disapproved by the State. Demonstrations, 1973-1987 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Jews in the USSR. Activities Disapproved by the State. Appeals, 1975-1988 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Jews in the USSR. Activities Disapproved by the State. Appeals to Soviet Authorities, 1976-1987 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Jews in the USSR. Activities Disapproved by the State. Appeals to West, 1972-1986 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Jews in the USSR. Leningrad Hijacking Case (1 of 7), 1970 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Jews in the USSR. Leningrad Hijacking Case (2 of 7), 1971 January - May (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Jews in the USSR. Leningrad Hijacking Case (3 of 7), 1971 May - December (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Jews in the USSR. Leningrad Hijacking Case (4 of 7), 1972-1973 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Jews in the USSR. Leningrad Hijacking Case (5 of 7), 1974 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Jews in the USSR. Leningrad Hijacking Case (6 of 7), 1975-1979 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Jews in the USSR. Leningrad Hijacking Case (7 of 7), 1980 - 1985, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Jews in the USSR. Emigration on Religious Ground, 1973-1988, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Jews in the USSR. Activities Disapproved by the State. Contacts with Foreigners and Emigrants, 1980-1986 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Jews in the USSR. Activities Disapproved by the State. Underground Publications, Samizdat, 1976-1982 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Jews in the USSR. Activities Disapproved by the State. Underground Publications. "Exodus", 1969-1971 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Jews in the USSR. Activities Disapproved by the State. Underground Publications. "Vestnik iskhoda", 1974 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Jews in the USSR. Activities Disapproved by the State. Underground Publications. "Jews in the USSR", 1975-1981 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Jews in the USSR. Activities Disapproved by the State. Unofficial Ecumenical Contacts, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Jewish Religion. Theology. Philosophy. Education. Ethics, 1967-1972, 1976, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Jewish Religion. Theology, 1976, 1978, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Jewish Religion. Individual Theologians. Kantorovich, Meir, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Jewish Religion and Secular Education, 1972, 1979-1985, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Jewish Religion. Theological Education, 1963-1987, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Jewish Religion and Intelligentsia, 1967, 1981, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Jewish Religion. Statistics, 1968-1987, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Jews in the USSR. Ecumenical Relations with Fellow Believers, 1966-1985 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Jews in the USSR. Ecumenical Relations with Fellow Believers. World Jewish Congress, 1975-1988 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Jews in the USSR. Relations with Other Denominations, 1978, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Jews in the USSR. Relations with Other Denominations. Relations with Christianity, 1978, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Jews in the USSR. Religion and National Identity, 1976-2000, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Jews in the USSR. Religion and National Identity. Jewish Autonomous Republic Birobidzhan, 1967-1992, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Jews in the USSR. Religion and National Identity. Individual Cases of Emigres or Refuseniks (1 of 4), 1970-1974 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Jews in the USSR. Religion and National Identity. Individual Cases of Emigres or Refuseniks (2 of 4), 1975-1980 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Jews in the USSR. Religion and National Identity. Individual Cases of Emigres or Refuseniks (3 of 4), 1981-1983 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Jews in the USSR. Religion and National Identity. Individual Cases of Emigres or Refuseniks (4 of 4), 1984-1988 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Jews in the USSR. Religion and National Identity. Israel and Zionism (1 of 4), 1967-1974 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Jews in the USSR. Religion and National Identity. Israel and Zionism (2 of 4), 1975-1976 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Jews in the USSR. Religion and National Identity. Israel and Zionism (3 of 4), 1975-1977 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Jews in the USSR. Religion and National Identity. Israel and Zionism (4 of 4), 1980-1992, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Jews in the USSR. Religion and National Identity. Extracts from Golda Meir's Book "My Life", 1975 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Jews in the USSR. Religion and National Identity. Judaism and Zionism, 1980, 1983, 1987, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Jews in the USSR. Religion and National Identity. Articles on Zionism, 1982-1988, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Jews in the USSR. Religion and National Identity. Reports on Middle East and Israeli-Russian Relations, 1980-1987 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Jews in the USSR. Religion and National Identity. Soviet Anti-Zionist Public Committee (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Jews in the USSR. Religion and National Identity. Language (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Emigration (1 of 18), 1966-1970 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Emigration (2 of 18), 1971 January-May (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Emigration (3 of 18), 1971 June-December (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Emigration (4 of 18), 1972 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Emigration (5 of 18), 1973 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Emigration (6 of 18), 1974 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Emigration (7 of 18), 1975 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Emigration (8 of 18), 1976 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Emigration (9 of 18), 1977 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Emigration (10 of 18), 1978 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Emigration (11 of 18), 1979 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Emigration (12 of 18), 1980 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Emigration (13 of 18), 1981-1982 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Emigration (14 of 18), 1983-1984 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Emigration (15 of 18), 1985 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Emigration (16 of 18), 1986 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Emigration (17 of 18), 1987 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Emigration (18 of 18), 1988-2002, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Emigration Regulations. OVIR, 1981-1987, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Official Soviet Pronouncements on Emigrations, 1981-1987 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Individual Emigres, 1981-1987 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Articles about Life of Emigres, 1975-1987 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Disappointment about Life in the West. Western Press Articles, 1972-1973, 1976, 1980, 1986-1987 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Disappointment about Life in the West. Soviet Press Articles, 1973-1986 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Nationalist Publications, 1971-1979, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Jewish Secular Culture, 1979-1982 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Anti-Semitism (1 of 6), 1964-1972 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Anti-Semitism (2 of 6), 1973-1979 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Anti-Semitism (3 of 6), 1980-1983 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Anti-Semitism (4 of 6), 1984-1986 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Anti-Semitism (5 of 6), 1987 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Anti-Semitism (6 of 6), 1988-2002, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Non-Religious and Cultural Activities (1 of 2), 1952, 1967-1976 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Non-Religious and Cultural Activities (2 of 2), 1977-1991, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Jewish Organizations' Involvement in Secular Affairs and Politics, 1976-1991, 1996, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Jewish Art, Architecture, Music, Literature. General, 1975-1989 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Jewish Art, Architecture, Music, Literature. Individuals, 1973-1988 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Jewish Music and Dance, 1974, 1977-1978, 1983, 1985-1987, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Jewish Art, 1975, 1980, 1986-1987 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Synagogue Architecture and Restoration, 1983-1984, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Jewish Art. Drama, 1980-1986 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Jewish Literature, 1968-1991, 2000, 2001, undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Jewish Literature. Talmud, 1970, 1977-1981, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Jewish Women, 1975, 1984-1987 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Jewish Children and Youth, 1975-1987 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Jews in the USSR. Sociology. Family, 1977-1987 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Jews in the USSR. Visual material, 1976-1984 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Jews in the USSR. Articles in Western Press, 1985-1993 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Jews in the USSR and Post-Soviet Russia. Articles in Soviet and Post-Soviet Press, 1988-1993 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Jews in the USSR and Post-Soviet Russia. Christian-Jewish Dialog, 1992-1993, undated (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Soviet Jewry. Russian Nationalism and Antisemitism. Conference Papers, 1982-1986, 1990, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Jews in the USSR. General References, 1973-1983, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Jews in the USSR and Post-Soviet Russia. Nationalism and Antisemitism (1 of 2), 1979-1998 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Jews in the USSR and Post-Soviet Russia. Nationalism and Antisemitism (2 of 2), 1978-1979, 1985, 1990, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Support for Refuseniks, 1986-1990, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Jews in the USSR. Travel and Immigration, 1986-1990, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Jews in the USSR. Criticism of Emigration in Soviet Press, 1980-1987 (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Samizdat, 1964-1987, undated; 2
  The series contains unofficially distributed information on discrimination and persecution of Jews in the Soviet Union. The materials include unofficially circulated trial records, petitions, appeals, and publications.
  - Manevich, G.M. Appeal to Chief Rabbi of Moscow Jewish Religious Community, 1971 March 31 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Manevich, G.M. Short Resume of Letter and Supplements Addressed to M.V. Keldysh (1 of 2), 1971 October-November (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Manevich, G.M. Short Resume of Letter and Supplements Addressed to M.V. Keldysh (2 of 2), 1971 October-November (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Individual Jews. Gluzman, Semyon, 1986-1981 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Oppressive Practices against Jewish Believers. General, 1971, 1977-1986 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Oppressive Practices against Jewish Believers. Harassment. Physical Assault, 1972, 1984, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Oppressive Practices against Jewish Believers. Interrogations, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Oppressive Practices against Jewish Believers. Trials. General, 1984-1986 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Oppressive Practices against Jewish Believers. Trials. Begun, Iosif, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Oppressive Practices against Jewish Believers. Trials. Edelshtein, Yuri, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Oppressive Practices against Jewish Believers. Trials. Lein, Aleksandra, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Oppressive Practices against Jewish Believers. Trials. Magarik, Aleksei, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Oppressive Practices against Jewish Believers. Trials. Pilnikov, Valerii, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Oppressive Practices against Jewish Believers. Trials. Volvovsky, Leonid, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Oppressive Practices against Jewish Believers. Trials. Zubko, Stanislav, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Oppressive Practices against Jewish Believers. Trials. Zunshain, Zakhar, 1984-1985 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Oppressive Practices against Jewish Believers. Imprisonment. General, 1979-1987 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Oppressive Practices against Jewish Believers. Imprisonment. Zunshain, Zakhar, 1984-1985 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Oppressive Practices against Jewish Believers. Attacks in the Media, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Oppressive Practices against Jewish Believers. House Searches, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Jewish Religious Life, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Jews in the USSR. International Contacts. General Appeals, 1985-1987 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Jews in the USSR. Activities Disapproved by the State. General, 1979, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Jewish Samizdat Publications. Leningrad Jewish Almanac, no.1, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. General, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Individual Cases of Refuseniks. General, 1983-1984, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Individual Cases of Refuseniks. Gorodetsky, Yakov and Polina, 1982-1983 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Individual Cases of Refuseniks. Nudel, Ida, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Emigration. Apekin, Vladimir, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Jewish Religion and National Identity. Antisemitism, undated (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Jews in the USSR. Involvement in Secular Affairs. Individual Laymen. Meiman, Naum, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Jews in the USSR. Appeal to Foreign Readers, 1984 September (Box 19, Folder 29)